Preliminary Guide to the Douglas M. Knight Records, 1949 - 1970
Duke University. University Archives
- Reports, 1951-1969 (Box 33)
  - Marine Laboratory, 1960-1968, [4 folders] (Box 35)
  - Medical School, 1960-1968 (Box 35)
  - Nursing, School of, 1960-1968 (Box 35)
  - Parapsychology Laboratory, 1962-1963 (Box 35)
  - Physical Education and Athletics, 1960-1967, [2 folders] (Box 35)
  - Physical Education [Women's College], 1960-1964 (Box 35)
  - Planning and Institutional Studies, 1960-1966 (Box 35)
  - Office of Regional Programs, 1966-1967, [2 folders] (Box 35)
  - Registrar, 1963-1964 (Box 35)
  - Research, Duke University Council on, 1963-1964 (Box 35)
  - Space Utilization Study, November, 1965 (Box 35)
  - Trinity College -- Office of the Dean, 1963-1964 (Box 35)
  - Woman's College, 1963-1964 (Box 35)
  - Annual Reports (Box 35)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 36)
    - President's Report to the Faculty, March 2, 1961; November 28, 1961 (Box 36)
    - President's Report to Trustees, November, 1962 and March 6, 1964 (Box 36)
    - President's [Appendices], 1962-1964 (Box 36)
    - Provost, 1960-1968, [2 folders] (Box 36)
    - Public Relations, V.P. for, 1960-1963 (Box 36)
    - Radio Station, 1960-1961 (Box 36)
    - Regional Programs, Office for, 1967-1968 (Box 36)
    - Registrar, 1955-1967, [2 folders] (Box 36)
    - Religious Activity, 1960-1963 (Box 36)
    - Secretary, Office of the, 1960-1962 (Box 36)
    - Special Projects [ABC-A Better Chance], 1966 (Box 36)
    - Student Health, 1960-1964 (Box 36)
    - Student Life, Division of, 1960-1963 (Box 36)
    - Student Union, 1960-1963 (Box 36)
    - Summary of Reports to the President, 1967-1968 (Box 36)
    - Summer Session, 1960-1968, [3 folders] (Box 36)
    - Survey, 1969 (Box 36)
    - Trinity College, 1960-1967 (Box 36)
    - University Council on Research, 1960-1967 (Box 36)
    - Woman's College, 1960-1967, [2 folders] (Box 36)
- Surveys, 1953-1968 (Box 36)
  Includes miscellaneous studies and surveys, which report on various aspects of the University, including faculty salaries, placement of doctoral students, departmental enrollment between 1935 and 1965, progress at Duke between 1940 and 1961, and a 1962 origin study of Duke graduate students.
  - Academic Calendars of Selected Institutions, 1966-1968 (Box 36)
  - Administrative Teaching Survey, Academic Year, 1964-1965 (Box 36)
  - American Council on Education, 1966 (Box 36)
  - Board Meetings -- Curriculum Changes, 1967 (Box 36)
  - Cooperative Summer Program for Students & Faculty in Disadvantaged Colleges, 1966-1967 (Box 36)
  - Cummins Engine Company Foundation, 1963-1965 (Box 36)
  - Duke University Faculty Salaries, 1966-1967 (Box 36)
  - Employees of Duke University, 1965 (Box 36)
  - Enrollment at Selected Private Universities, 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - Graduation Requirements, Calendar, Course Load at Selected Institutions (Box 36)
  - Identification Card Proposal, Addressograph Plastic Plates, 1966 (Box 36)
  - Independent Study of Duke University, March 1965 (Box 36)
  - Keydex Topics (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous, [2 folders] (Box 36)
  - Orientation to the Institute (by Brinkley, W. L. Jr.) (Box 36)
  - Origin Study of Duke Graduate Students, Fall 1953-Spring 1962 (Box 36)
  - Questionnaires (Box 36)
    - Complete U.S.O.E., 1967-1968 (Box 36)
    - Study for the AAC Commission on College Administration, 1966 (Box 36)
    - American Council on Education, 1967-1968 (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 36)
      - From Colleges and Universities, 1965-1968 (Box 36)
      - From Commercial Publications, 1965-1968 (Box 36)
      - Individuals, 1966-1967 (Box 36)
      - Southern Association for Colleges and Schools, 1965-1967 (Box 36)
      - U. S. Government, 1965-1968 (Box 36)
    - Private School Enrollment Data, Feb. 1966 (Box 36)
  - Ph.D. Placement Study -- Final Report, 1962 (Box 36)
  - Summer Session Enrollments -- Selected Years, 1962-1965 (Box 36)
  - Departmental Enrollment at Duke over the last 30 years [1933-1965] (Box 36)
  - Enrollment Projections, 1966-1967 (Box 36)
  - Student Enrollment and Statistics, 1963-1966 (Box 36)
  - Student Enrollment and Statistical Data, 1963-1965 (Box 36)
  - Student Government -- Teacher Course Evaluation, 1966 (Box 36)
  - Students, 1964-1965 (Box 36)
  - North Carolina College Conference: Report, August 1964 (Box 36)
  - Tuition and Fees Study -- Selected Eastern and Southern Colleges & Universities, 1961-1966, [2 folders] (Box 36)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools. Departmental Breakdown Questionnaire, 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - Special Advising Survey, 1961-1965 (Box 36)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1968 (Box 36)
  - Wessel Report -- Duke's Advances from 1940-1962 (Box 36)
  - Woman's College -- Historical Sketch, 1968 (Box 36)
  - Year Round Operations -- Enrollment (Box 36)
- Inauguration and Videorecording Series, 1963 and 1969 (Box 36)
  Includes clippings, citations and formal greetings, and printed matter from the inauguration of Douglas Knight. Also includes a videotape recording of the inaugural ceremonies, which was recorded and broadcast by WUNC-TV, as well as interview with Knight that was recorded on April 21, 1969. The interview is titled "The Office of the President".
  - Inauguration, 1963 (Box 38)
  - Inauguration and Videorecordings, 1963-1969 (Box 39)
- Student Cases [RESTRICTED] (Box 39)
  Includes correspondence about individual students' problems and concerns. These materials are closed except by permission of the University Archivist.
  - Student Cases [RESTRICTED] (Box 40)
- Oversize (Box 40)
  - Oversize materials (Box 41)
    - Blueprints (Box 41)
      - Chapel, Basement floor plan from Duke University Plant Engineering Department, 15 April 1966, drawn by P.H. Edwards (Box 41)
      - Proposed Lounge-Reception Room (existing Town Girls Lounge) (Box 41)
      - Science Building Center Wing by Carr Harrison Pruden and De Pasquale (2) (Box 41)
    - CORE newsletters, nos. 1-5, 1963-1964 (Box 41)
    - Duke University Enrollment Statistics, 1963-1964, 1966-1967 (Box 41)
    - Duke University Press (Box 41)
      - Balance Sheets, 1966-1967 (Box 41)
      - Statement of Profit and (Loss), 30 June 1966 (Box 41)
      - Statement of Income and Expenditures, 1966-1967 (Box 41)
    - Maps (Box 41)
      - Duke University Marine Laboratory no. 6 Beaufort, NC Durham County Tax Maps, 1964 (Box 41)
      - Area of Korstian Division, Duke Forest Orange and Durham Counties, February 1968 (Box 41)
    - Memorandum on the North Carolina Speaker Ban Law (Box 41)
    - Newspapers (Box 41)
      - Carolina Labor News vol.25, no.46 4 March 1966 (Box 41)
      - Chronicle of Higher Education, vol. II, no. 20 1 July 1968 (Box 41)
      - Untitled paper published by Local 77 "The crisis on our campus does not appear to be over. This paper provides relevant background information on labor abuses at Duke and on collective bagaining [sic]" (Box 41)
      - Durham Mornin' Herald, Armageddon edition 30 February 1967 (Box 41)
    - Opportunities for Community Service, Duke YM-YWCA (Box 41)
    - Organizational Chart for Duke University (Box 41)
      - undated (Box 41)
      - February 1968 (Box 41)
    - Toward a new city a conference on urban change, Duke University 4-6 October 1968 (Box 41)
Separated Material
These oversize items were seperated from the collection and are located in Map Cabinet drawer 20: Blueprints, Auditorium, Horace Trumbauer
Related Material
[Forms part of:] Duke University President records.
University Archives, Duke University
Allen Building Takeover, 1969 Collection
University Archives, Duke University
Cameron, Edmund McCullough "Eddie" Papers, 1941-1972
University Archives, Duke University
Division of Student Affairs, Administration Records, 1923-
University Archives, Duke University
Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Records, 1927-1968
University Archives, Duke University
Provost, Office of Records, 1960-1970
University Archives, Duke University
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Records
University Archives, Duke University
Women's College Records
University Archives, Duke University